postcodelottery.co.uk 2017-02-01

# People's Postcode Lottery Privacy Policy

People's Postcode Lottery is committed to protecting the personal information of all its service users. We recognise our obligation to keep personal information secure and believe that it is important for our customers to know how we treat their personal information. This policy applies to personal information collected by People's Postcode Lottery Ltd. about applicants to, and players of, People's Postcode Lottery and visitors to its website(s). The lottery is administered by People's Postcode Lottery Limited, a member of the Novamedia group of companies, which is the data controller of the information collected for the purposes of the lottery.

By applying to participate in People's Postcode Lottery or using the People's Postcode Lottery website(s) you acknowledge that you have read the terms of this policy and that you consent to the use of your personal information for the purposes and in the manner set out in this policy.

If you do not wish to provide your personal information on the basis set out in this policy you should not provide your personal information. In that case, we regret that you will not be able to participate in People's Postcode Lottery.

We may from time to time make changes to this policy. This page always offers the most recent information on our privacy policy.

Postcode Lottery Limited complies with the United Kingdom Data Protection Act 1998, Human Rights Act, 1998 and e-Privacy Regulations, 2003, in the collection and processing of personal information.

## Cookies:

**People's Postcode Lottery will only employ cookies (that is, small data files that are downloaded to your computer) to store the necessary transaction information during your visit to our website(s). For security reasons, there is never any personal data stored in our cookies. Most Internet browsers will allow you to change settings so that they do not accept cookies, although this may impair the operation of our website(s).**

## Information collected: 

People's Postcode Lottery collects personal information (name, address, date of birth, email address, etc.) about applicants and players, principally during the registration process. We will let you know if we are requesting any information that is not essential to the process. We also collect personal information about your participation in the lottery - for example, information about prizes and about your visits to our website(s).

We collect information directly from applicants and players when they voluntarily submit their personal information to us. At certain parts of our web site, we may provide the opportunity for users to register to use our services or request information. 

When this sort of information is collected we will provide the reason for collecting the information and how the information will be used. We reserve the right to add to this list of opportunities available to our users to interact with us. It is completely up to users to provide us with their personal information.

## Use of collected information:

Generally, our existing and potential customers are informed of the use of their personal information at the time of collection. Personal information provided to us or collected by us will be used to respond to inquiries, process requests or provide our services and these may include:

  * administering People's Postcode Lottery and generally providing the services requested of us;
  * preparing demographic statistics;
  * displaying appropriate individualised advertisements and content on our website(s);
  * complying with legal and regulatory obligations;
  * sending you written communications to announce important service changes, new features, technical issue updates and news about other Novamedia group products and services.

If you do not wish to receive such written communications from us and/or from other organisations please notify us (see Legal rights below).

Telephone calls to and from our Customer Experience team are recorded for training and security purposes.

People's Postcode Lottery will not send you unsolicited information including email regarding any third party commercial offers or advertisments.

## Disclosures of personal information:

We may disclose your information to other companies that we have contracted with to provide services to us or on our behalf. The organizations that we disclose personal data to are obliged to comply with rules on data protection, information security, confidentiality and access control. In order to set out the standard to be adhered to in any data-sharing activity, People's Postcode Lottery will put a data-sharing protocol in place to ensure that such third party organizations are processing personal data in compliance with the law. People's Postcode Lottery may, therefore, disclose personal data: 

  * to agents who process your information on our behalf under strict security and confidentiality
  * conditions
  * to process payment requests via financial institutions; 
  * where we believe in good faith that we need to do so to comply with the law or in the course of legal process or to protect the interests of our players and/or of our beneficiaries;
  * or with your consent. 

## Links:

Our websites may contain links to other sites. Although utmost care is exercised in providing links to sites that share our high standards, People's Postcode Lottery shall not be responsible for the content, security, availability and privacy practices used by such linked sites. 

The linked pages are provided for the convenience of our site users only and do not constitute an approval of their services or practices. Links from other websites to our home page do not require prior permission from us but deep linking into any other page of our site should not be effected without prior permission from us.

## Legal rights:

You have legal rights of access to personal information that we hold about you and may review or update any personal information that is provided to us or collected through this website on written request to us. You can also inform us that you do not want us to send you written communications as discussed in "What type of information we collect and how it is used", above. If you want to exercise these rights or have any queries regarding this policy please e-mail [info@postcodelottery.co.uk](mailto:info@postcodelottery.co.uk)

## Security statement:

As information security is critical to our activities People's Postcode Lottery attaches a lot of importance to the security of personal information. We handle personal information with commitment to ensure a secure environment that can be trusted to fulfil all confidentiality requirements. Documented steps are taken to safeguard information according to established security standards and procedures and we continually assess and use cutting-edge technology for protecting information.

Personal and confidential information used in transactions is kept confidential. People's Postcode Lottery is committed to ensuring information confidentiality through the use of state-of-the-art information security practices, controls, policies and procedures. 

People's Postcode Lottery uses and maintains strict physical, electronic and administrative safeguards to protect user's personal information from unauthorised or inappropriate access. Personal information collected by us is stored in secure operating environments that are not accessible by the public. Employees, business partners and affiliates who misuse a user's personal information are subject to legal or disciplinary actions.

The company uses a comprehensive and effective security management program for the purpose of eliminating the risks posed by potential threats to the company's electronic information resources. The controls that have been put in place work to ensure that the company’s systems are protected against unauthorised access, disclosure, modification or destruction. Any person or group that accesses the company’s web-site and other e-systems must, however, recognise the responsibility to preserve the security and confidentiality of resources/systems and respect the right of other users.

_© 2014 People's Postcode Lottery's Privacy Policy and Security Statement have been last updated: 25th June 2014_

If you need any assistance, please see our Help page or Contact Us.
